What's going on you guys? Welcome back
to the YouTube channel. My name is Brian
Rodriguez and today we're doing another
product review. I want to thank our
partners XVive for once again sending a
product for us to review. First we
started out with the P3 Bluetooth system
and today we're doing the U35 microphone
wireless system. This is a really cool
product because it could be used as a
transmitter or receiver. So, let's take
a closer look and show you guys what
we're talking about. See you on the next
clip. We're now going to do a quick
unboxing of this product for you guys.
The box that it comes in is very nice,
very high quality.
Open this thing up and show you guys
what's inside as well.
So, we've got our manual here.
Comes with a beautiful carrying case
here. Keep your product nice and
protected.
They also send a pamphlet with other
products that X5 make,
which by the way, we highly recommend on
this channel. This is a P3 I was telling
you guys about that X5 also sent to us
that we have a review on this channel if
you guys want to check it out. So,
that's always cool.
your warranty card,
your charging cable.
So, this is USBC.
What's very cool is you have a one
regular USB, I believe these are to USBC
on both sides. So, you could charge both
units with one charging port or one
power supply. And when I flip this over,
we have our product here.
Now, one thing to note, this is made of
metal and plastic.
It's got a nice heavy feel. Like, this
is not a cheap product whatsoever.
You can see here, this is all metal.
Very nice construction. Now, let's take
a quick look at the two units. On the
left side, we have your transmitter. On
the right side, we have the receiver.
Really nice. Once again, you have your
switch for mic and line. The mic is
going to give you zero zero dB input
signal strength. The line side will give
you -10 decel of input signal strength.
The mic will be stronger, of course,
that way you have a little more gain.
You have your onoff switch or on and
mute. This is the button to select
between the channels. You have a total
of six channels. And the button in the
middle, you can flick in between them.
You'll have, if you have no uh light on
this, that means you have 100% to 30%,
but once a solid red light comes, that
means you're under 30%, so you should
start charging it. If it's flickering
red, you'll have less than 10%. This on
the bottom is the charging in the the
transmitting antenna.
Same thing goes for the receiver. You
got just your power on. You could change
the channel. You have one through six
channels. And then this means you're all
linked up together.
You also have your battery indicator
light. Same thing. If you have no light,
that means you're over 100% to 30. Under
30, you'll have solid red. Under 10, you
will, of course, have flickering red
light. To get a full 5 hour battery life
on these, you would have to charge them
for 2 and 1/2 hours. So, these will last
you 5 hours of of steady signal, which
is good cuz most events here are four to
five hours. So, that gives you plenty of
usage.
If you charge it for about an hour and
15, you're going to get 2 hours. If you
charge it for 30 minutes, you're going
to get 1 hour. When the lights are
green, that means you got 41% to 100%.
Yellow light means you got 6% to 40%.
Red means you're under 5%. Red blinking,
you got under 1%. So, here in the back,
it'll show you a few options of how you
could use this as a dynamic microphone
transmitter or a mixer transmitter. You
could also use it for like a if you have
a satellite speaker at the end of the
room where you want it, you don't want
to run a cord, you could just plug it
into the outlet and then use this as
your signal transmission. You have six
channels like we mentioned, less than 5
milliseconds of latency, 5 hours of
battery, a wide 20 Hz to 20k herz
frequency response, which is pretty much
the maximum. High resolution 24bit
audio,
110 dB of dynamic range. You have about
100 foot signal range that also depends
on the RF signal absorbing reflection
and interference. 100 ft is plenty of
room about 33 m. So yeah, now let me
show you this working and um show you
guys what it sounds like. I also just
want to show you guys, sorry I have
sweaty hands. [laughter] I want to show
you guys if you know once you're going
through the channels, the light will
turn green on your receiver once you
have a pair. So right here I'm on
channel two. So this is one, two, bam,
the light will go on. If I switch it to
channel three, now we lose connection.
So you'll know you have connection once
you have a green light.
Bam. So let's test this out now. So
right now I'm just going to show you how
quickly we can turn an old school
microphone. I've had this 15 years.
We're now going to make this a wireless
microphone.
So we're going to do is we're going to
drive our transmitter here.
Plug it in.
This is now a wireless microphone. our
receiver. We're gonna plug it into our
mixer.
Turn this on. Put it on microphone
switch.
We are on line one here. Line one here.
We have a green light. So, we should be
connected. And yes, we are connected.
Now, you could see how well and good
this sounds. Very crispy. I have low
tone. I use my microphone a lot. And I'd
have no problem using this. If you have
an emergency situation, something goes
bad with your microphone or if you just
want to use this, there's nothing wrong
with it either. It's just going to hang
out of your microphone, but it is a good
solution to have. I could see this
mostly being used to deploy speakers far
away or if you got a mixer that you want
to put in the other side of the room,
you know, either way. But as a
microphone transmitter, it works great
as well. As you can see, it's very
crispy. No dropouts. I know I'm right
next to it. I could walk down the
hallway here and show you guys.
So, let me walk over here. So, this is
about 20 ft. I'm going to keep walking.
If I keep going down here this way, I
don't know if you guys can see me. This
is going to be 40 ft about.
So, I haven't dropped out at all. Still
working good. Walking back. Welcome
back. No dropouts whatsoever. Still
crystal clear.
No issues. So, that's about 40 ft. We
had a wall in between and no issues
whatsoever. So, I hope that gives you
guys an idea of what we could do. And
now, let's show it with a speaker rather
than a microphone. So, now we're going
to transmit the signal. All right. Well,
we're transmitting now, but we're going
to transmit audio music instead of a
microphone. All right. See you on the
next clip. So, now we kind of have this
set up a little bit differently. So, now
the transmitter is on the output of our
mixer. So, we're sending signal out and
we're receiving it with the speaker. So,
you see the receiver back there in the
speaker. [singing]
So, this will work great if you have a
speaker that you want to put far away in
the other side of the room or you have a
multiple room setup. As long as you're
within that 100 ft, you should be okay.
We also flick the switch on the
transmitter to the line. And as you can
see, it sounds great.
>> [music]
[clears throat]
[music]
>> And that, my friends, is the review of
the XVive U35 microphone wireless
system. I hope I was able to show you
guys and kind of explain how it works.
You're kind of doing the same thing
where you're sending the signal either
from a mixer or from a microphone, but
you're setting it up the opposite where
now you have the transmitter on the
mixer and the receiver on the speaker
rather than having the receiver on the
mixer and the transmitter on the
microphone. I hope that made sense. But
this works really well. Crystal clear
sound. The batteries do work for 5
hours. I have tried them. I've used this
at like a deployed it in a different
room where people wanted to hear the
music, but not, you know, I didn't need
to be there, but just as background
sound to what was going on at the main
event. So, that was cool. So, we had a
bar area. I had a speaker there so
people could still be at the bar
listening to what was going on at the
party, hear any announcements and stuff
like that, but I didn't have to run a
wire. So, I got to the bar, put the
speaker plugged into the outlet, put my
transmitter and receiver in. I'm still
doing my party, doing the vibe.
Everything is in the reception room, but
at the bar, people could still know. So,
if I'm making an announcement, like
there's the cake cutting about to
happen, people could leave from the bar
and head over to the party. So, that's
it. Everything XVive is very well built,
great customer service. Anytime I've had
a problem, I reach out to them. But, um,
fortunately, the only time we've had to
reach out is to do product reviews
because I've never had an issue yet.
Like I said, the quality is great. All
metal construction. I could see this,
you know, lasting a long time. I've had
my P3 already 3 four years and uh with
without any issues. So yeah, I hope you
guys liked the video. If you did, if you
have any questions, please like,
comment, I can reach out to X5 for you
guys or try to help you with any
questions I could answer. And yeah, I'll
leave a link on the bottom so you guys
can get a discount and uh buy this for
yourselves. And uh I'll see you guys in
the next video. All right, we have some
giglog footage that we haven't put
together yet, but we're going to start
releasing. So, I'll see you guys in the
next video. You guys have it going and
see you in the next video. Keep them
rocking. Peace.